James E. McDonald papers, (1904-1997)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
James E. McDonald papers, 1904-1997
MS 412
McDonald, James E., 1920-1971
Papers, 1904-1997 (bulk 1958-1971). Mostly correspondence, cases, reports, interviews, and printed materials relating to James E. McDonald's investigations, 1958 to 1971, into unidentified flying objects and similar sightings.
66 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
Born in 1920 in Duluth, Minnesota, James E. McDonald was educated at the University of Omaha (B.A. Chemistry, 1942), Massachusetts Institute of Technology (M.S. Meteorology, 1945), and Iowa State College (Ph.D. Physics, 1951). He served in the United States Navy from 1942 to 1945, and, for the following years taught or researched at Naval Aerology School, Iowa State College, and University of Chicago. He married Betsy Hunt in 1945, and they had six children.
He was appointed Associate Director at the University of Arizona's Institute of Atmospheric Physics from 1954 until 1956, and was a professor in that department from 1956 until his death in 1971. His areas of research included cloud physics, weather modification, and micrometeorology. Internationally known, he was a member of the National Academy of Sciences, American Meteorological Society, American Geophysical Union, and other national and international societies. Relentless in his pursuit of knowledge and understanding, Mr. McDonald was an inspiring lecturer and continuously active in university affairs.
He was the author of Physics of Cloud Modification, in the fifth volume of Advances in Geophysics, and served as contributing editor to The Glossary of Meteorology, and contributed many articles to his filed of study. His scientific interests also led him to contribute writings and testimony to contemporary issues of his time such as the supersonic transport debates, placement of Titan II missiles around the Tucson basin, and scientific dismissal of unidentified flying objects. His hypothesis that UFOs were extraterrestrial instruments on information gathering missions, and his beliefs that current scientific reports, such as the Condon Report, were superficially done, led him to investigate sightings and combat governmental impediments into his research topics.
Organization
This collection is organized into two subgroups. Subgroup one has seven series. Subgroup two has one series.
Subgroup I: UFO Research Files 1904-1971
Series I: General Files, A-Z, 1945-1971
Series II: Project Blue Book Radar-visual Files and Reports, 1947-1968
Series III: Research Files, 1904-1969
Series IV: Publications on Project Grudge, Blue Book, Condon, Others, 1951-1969
Series V: Photographic Materials,
Series VI: Audio-tapes: Interviews of Witnesses by JEM, 1954-1967
Series VII: Supplemental Materials, 1960-1971
Subgroup II: General Research Files 1953-1997
Series I: Research Files, 1953-1997
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1904-1997 (bulk 1958-1971). Mostly correspondence, cases, reports, interviews, and printed materials relating to James E. McDonald's investigations, 1958 to 1971, into unidentified flying objects and similar sightings, and governmental investigations, responses and reports, including the United States Air Force's Project Blue Book, and Edward U. Condon's 1969 report, A Scientific Study of Unidentified Flying Objects, relating to these phenomenon. Correspondence, 1958-1971, is between McDonald and various government and military officials, other scientific and professional UFO researchers. Case files, 1945-1970, include investigations, mostly in the United States, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand, on sightings by military pilots, tower control officers, law enforcement officers, scientists and citizens.
Contains photocopies of approximately 580 Project Blue Book sighting reports, mostly by pilots, and some with airborne and ground radar verification. Also includes four handwritten journals, 1958-1971, describing UFO investigative activity; papers and talks, 1966-1977, given before conferences, symposia, and groups; research materials, including his 1967 trip to Australia and New Zealand; a referenced outline of an unpublished book; over 80 audio-tapes of interviews, talks, and conversations on UFO topics; photographic materials on various subjects; and supplemental materials.
Access Terms
Unidentified flying objects -- Case studies
Unidentified flying objects -- Government policy -- United States
Unidentified flying objects -- History
Unidentified flying objects -- Sightings and encounters
Condon, Edward Uhler, 1902-1974
McDonald, James E., 1920-
National Investigations Committee on Aerial Phenomena
Project Blue Book (U.S.)
United States. -- Air Technical Intelligence Center
Correspondence
Photographs
Container List
- Subgroup I: UFO Research Files, 1904-1971
  - Series I: General Files, A-Z, 1945-1971
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science. Arizona Section. 4/29/67 (Box 1)
    - AAAS: 2/69 (Box 1)
    - AAAS: Summary of Presentations (1 of 2). 12/69 (Box 1)
    - AAAS: Miscellaneous items. (Box 1)
    - ABC-TV. 1/6/69 (Box 1)
    - Accidents: A/C, Cars. (Box 1)
    - Adams, Don: Edgemont, NM, close-arm fire case. 4/28/67 (Box 1)
    - Adamski, George. (Box 1)
    - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA): Cape Kennedy, FL. 12/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Chicago. 9/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Huntsville, Alabama. 5/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Los Angeles Area. 3/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Los Angeles. 5/6/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Mansfield State College, PA. 4/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: New York City. 1/70 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Oklahoma City. 11/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Omaha, Nebraska. 11/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Phoenix, AZ. 10/68 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Physics Colloquium, Ames, Iowa. 4/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Pt. Mugu, CA. 2/18/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Sacramento, CA. 5/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Salt Lake City. 3/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: San Antonio, TX. 2/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: San Diego, CA. 3/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Seattle, WA. 8/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Subcommittee and General. (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Tucson: Potter Correspondence. 7/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Tulsa, Oklahoma. 5/69 (Box 1)
    - AIAA: Vandenberg AFB, CA. 4/69 (Box 1)
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (AFOSR). (Box 1)
    - Air Force Policy: Witnesses, Reports. (Box 1)
    - Airship Cases Aldrich, Jan: Correspondence. 1967 (Box 1)
    - Allende Letters: Carlos Miguel: aka Carl Allen. (Box 1)
    - Amarillo, TX. 3/68 (Box 1)
    - American Express: Dead file. (Box 1)
    - American Meteorological Society (AMS) Banquet: Chicago. 5/68 (Box 1)
    - AMS-Air Weather Service 9/17/70: Greater St. Louis area. (Box 1)
    - AMS: Miami. 11/68 (Box 1)
    - AMS: DCA Symposium Meteorological observations & instruments. (Box 1)
    - Anderson, John A.: Savannah River AEC. 1952 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Juanita: Sacramento, CA. 1/1/69 (Box 1)
    - Angel Hair. (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor, MI: Grenier Kartlick. 3/25/66 (Box 1)
    - Animal Reaction Cases Appleton, Mrs. Frank: Elgin, AZ. 12/4/69 (Box 1)
    - Aerial Phenomena Research Organization (APRO). (Box 1)
    - Arizona Cases. (Box 1)
    - Arizona Medical School Colloquium. 1/69 (Box 1)
    - Arnold, Kenneth. 1947 (Box 1)
    - Artesia, NM. 1/16/51 (Box 1)
    - Ashburn, PA. 3/10/67 (Box 1)
    - American Society of Newspaper Editors (ASNE). 5/67 (Box 1)
    - Assurances: Air Force & Government. (Box 1)
    - Astronomical Sky Surveys. (Box 1)
    - Astronauts: Official Documents. (Box 1)
    - Australia: Auckland: Brunt, A. J. (Box 1)
    - Australia: Clips. (Box 1)
    - Australia: Haylock, Dan: Paynesville, Victoria. (Box 1)
    - Australia: Nowra Naval Air Station. 1954 (Box 1)
    - Australian Correspondence. 1967 (Box 1)
    - Australian Flying Saucer Magazine. (Box 1)
    - Australian Miscellaneous Sightings: Slides, Sullivan, Westall school sightings. (Box 1)
    - Australian Miscellany. (Box 1)
    - Australian photos, JEM: Radio Station 2 GB. (Box 1)
    - Australian photos, Balwyn and Coyle cases. (Box 1)
    - Australian Sightings: Paul Norman. (Box 1)
    - Australian Trip Materials: Sighting catalog cards. (Box 1)
    - Australian Tully "nests" (photo). (Box 1)
    - Australian UFO Bulletin: Victorian UFO Research Society. (Box 1)
    - Aviation Week & Space Technology: early Klass, Phillip correspondence. (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Terry: Photos case (multiple), Catalina Island See also Photographs. (Box 2)
    - Baker, R. M. L.. 1968 (Box 2)
    - Ball Lightning. (Box 2)
    - Baseball studies, James E. McDonald. (Box 2)
    - Baytown, TX. 7/18/66 (Box 2)
    - BBC: Philip Daly. 1967 (Box 2)
    - Beallsville, Ohio: Greg Wells "burn case." 3/19/68 (Box 2)
    - Beatty, James C.: Ground Observer Corps (GOC). 9/54 (Box 2)
    - Beeps: San Jose, CA area: Los Gatos. (Box 2)
    - Beeps: Washington State: McClelland, Betty. (Box 2)
    - Bellefontaine, Ohio 8/1/52: Radar/Aircraft/Visual. (Box 2)
    - Benedek, Leslie: Perth, Australia. 1/17/67 (Box 2)
    - Benson, N. E.: Wallingford, Connecticut. 5/28/67 (Box 2)
    - Benton, T. Bruce: Spring 1952: USAF radar case. (Box 2)
    - Berkner, Lloyd & Johnson, S. W.: Southwest Center for Advanced Studies visit. 4/15/67 (Box 2)
    - Beverly, Massachusetts Case. 3/22/66 (Box 2)
    - Bibliographical Lists of Published JEM Scientific Papers. (Box 2)
    - Bigg, E. K.: Australia: Correspondence. 1968 (Box 2)
    - Bloecher, Ted. 1966 (Box 2)
    - Bloecher, Ted: (1 of 3). 1967 (Box 2)
    - Bloecher, Ted. 1968 (Box 2)
    - Bloecher, Ted. 1969 (Box 2)
    - Bloecher, Ted:. 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Blue Book. 1966 (Box 2)
    - Blue Book. 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Blue Book: Grudge Reports Preface. 1968 (Box 2)
    - Blue Book: Re-evaluations. (Box 2)
    - Blue Book: Termination. Book Authoring. 1969 (Box 2)
    - Booth, Lloyd C.: Conway, SC. 1/29/53 (Box 2)
    - Bradford, IL. 3/18/50 (Box 2)
    - Branch, David: NICAP Affilate, Los Angeles, CA. (Box 2)
    - Bresler, Dr. Jack: Car-shaking case: Displacement cases. (Box 2)
    - Brew, Charlie: 2/15/63. (Box 2)
    - Bridge, William: San Diego, CA. (Box 2)
    - British Overseas Airways Corp. (BOAC). 6/29/54 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Helen (Auto case). 1967 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Capt. Jack: Mt. Shasta, CA. 7/66 (Box 2)
    - Browning, Dr. Iben. 3/22/69 (Box 2)
    - Browning, Rev. Lionel. 12/4/60 (Box 2)
    - Bruns, Edward: Herman, Minnesota. 12/20/65 (Box 2)
    - Bryan, Kenneth: US Weather Bureau. 3/8/67 (Box 2)
    - Burgess, Howard F.: Sandia Corp. (Box 2)
    - Burns: Irradiation: Heat. 1/96 (Box 2)
    - Burns, Gov. Haydon: Ocala, FL. 4/25/66 (Box 2)
    - Burns, Horace: Stanton, VA. 12/21/62 (Box 2)
    - Burro Club Civil Aeronautics Administration (CAA): Terra Haute, Indiana. 11/9/51 (Box 2)
    - Cale, Clifford J.: Canadian National. 3/66 (Box 2)
    - Campeadore, Michael. 5/6/67 (Box 2)
    - Camp Lejeune, North Carolina. 4/28/67 (Box 2)
    - Canada Canadian Pacific Airways, Peru. (Box 2)
    - Canadian Symposium: U. of Toronto, McGill Univ. (Box 2)
    - Burns, Gov. Haydon: Ocala, FL. 4/25/66 (Box 2)
    - Burns, Horace: Stanton, VA. 12/21/62 (Box 2)
    - Burro Club Civil Aeronautics Administration (CAA): Terra Haute, Indiana. 11/9/51 (Box 2)
    - Cale, Clifford J.: Canadian National. 3/66 (Box 2)
    - Campeadore, Michael. 5/6/67 (Box 2)
    - Camp Lejeune, North Carolina. 4/28/67 (Box 2)
    - Canada Canadian Pacific Airways, Peru. (Box 2)
    - Canadian Symposium: U. of Toronto, McGill Univ. (Box 2)
    - Canal Zone 11/25/52 (Declassified BB case, Condon Report). (Box 2)
    - Canberry Airport. 7/15/65 (Box 2)
    - Civil Air Patrol Conference. (Box 2)
    - Carr, Donald R., San Diego. 5/13/52 (Box 2)
    - Carstoiu, John: International Consultant Scientist Corp. (Box 2)
    - Carswell AFB, TX 2/13/53. (Box 2)
    - Cartoons. (Box 2)
    - Cathie, Capt. Bruce L. (Box 2)
    - CBS: "CBS Reports: UFO, Friend, Foe or Fantasy," Transcript. (Box 2)
    - Cerny, Paul C.: Bay Area. (Box 2)
    - Charleston, West VA: Braniff Airlines pilot. 5/4/66 (Box 2)
    - Chay, Donald S.: United Airlines pilot. 6/24/?5 (Box 2)
    - Cherry Creek, NY. 8/65 (Box 2)
    - Childerhose, Robert J. 8/27/56 (Box 2)
    - Chiles-Whitted sighting. 9/24/48 (Box 2)
    - China Lake, CA. 1/18/66 (Box 3)
    - China Lake, CA: Bickel, Walt: Sightings, time-lapse case. (Box 3)
    - China Lake: Research Society of America Speech. 5/27/69 (Box 3)
    - China Lake: McArtor, Marie. (Box 3)
    - Clapp, Carol: Ravenna, Ohio. 1967 (Box 3)
    - Clarke, Arthur C. (Box 3)
    - Cloud Holes: Pictures. (Box 3)
    - Cloud Seeding: "Increasing Rain Artificially," JEM. 9/17/56 (Box 3)
    - Clouds: UFO Coarsegold, surrounding area: E. E. (Bud) Miller, Dan Wallis. (Box 3)
    - Coffman, Hubert: Exeter, CA. 1/10/68 (Box 3)
    - Collins, Mrs. D. J.: Lennox, MA. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Clippings. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Colorado Springs. 5/13/67 (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Condon, JEM correspondence. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Correspondence, Levine, Norman. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Correspondence Low, JEM. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Correspondence Low, miscellaneous. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Extension proposed. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Home file. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Library project file. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Memo: Robert Low. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: 100 Best List. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Original: Early proposals. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Referrals to JEM. (Box 3)
    - Condon Committee: Saunders, David: Correspondence. (Box 3)
    - Condon, Dr. E. U.: Correspondence with J. E. McDonald. (Box 3)
    - Condon, Dr. E. U.: Miscellaneous & Corres. (Box 3)
    - Condon, Dr. E. U.: UFOs I Have Loved and Lost. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Basic Items: Cases, NAS, etc. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Cartoons, correspondence, etc. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: R-B47#3 Louisiana to Texas. 7/17/57 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #3 Haneda AFB, Japan. 8/5/52 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #7 Provo, Utah. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #35 Vandenberg AFB. 10/6/6 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report also Vandenberg AFB Trip. 3/16/69 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #41 Charleston, WVA. 12/2/67 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #49: Tremonton, UT Newhouse film: (Interview Tape #60). 7/2/52 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #54 Gulfstream. 3/11/66 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case #55, Farmington, NM: Photo. 4/22/65 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: p. 141: Kirtland AFB: Correspondence, photos. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: pp. 145-48: Hess, Seymour. 5/20/50 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: p. 14 McChord AFB: Seattle,. 10/2/59 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case: Springfield, MA: Gasslein: See JEM article in file. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case: Kincheloe AFB (also see Kincheloe); Newcastle, PA; Edwards. (Box 3)
    - AFB; Cape Ann; Minot AFB. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Case: Ward, Madeline, 53: Hampton Bay, Long Island, NY. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Clippings & Miscellaneous. Jan-Dec 1969 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Correspondence on cases, CU library archives, etc. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Criticisms (Also see Carl Sagan file). (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Criticisms by JEM. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Critique: NICAP. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Finland AFS, MN 9/5-6-/66. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: JEM Letters re: Science article. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Levine, Norman E. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Nash / Fortenberry classic case: See "Nash." (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: National Academy of Sciences assessment. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: NAS Panel Review. 1/8/69 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Paste-ups. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Project Grudge: Important cases. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Review in Scientific American v. 220, no. 4, April 1, 1969. 1963 (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Stripped copies of paperback edition. (Box 3)
    - Condon Report: Thayer, Gordon. (Box 3)
    - Congressional Hearing, UFO: Comm. On Science & Astron: JEM statement. 7/29/68 (Box 4)
    - Congressional Record: Proxmire, William. 1/15/71 (Box 4)
    - Congressional UFO Investigations. 1968 (Box 4)
    - Conte, Silvio O. April 1971 (Box 4)
    - Contson, Frank H.: Gatesburg, IL. 3/6/67 (Box 4)
    - Continental Divide: Radar-Visual case. 1/26/53 (Box 4)
    - Controversies & Unorthodoxies, Past & Present. (Box 4)
    - Cooney, Stuart: Pacifica Radio. 1968 (Box 4)
    - Cooper, Earl: Muroc AFB 7/8/67 (See closed tape #28). (Box 4)
    - Cooper, Gordon: Astronaut sighting. 5/16/63 (Box 4)
    - Corning, CA. 7/4/67 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1966 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1968 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1969 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1970 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Researchers from other countries. (Box 4)
    - Coverup vs. foul-up. (Box 4)
    - Coyle, John: Photos. 3/5/67 (Box 4)
    - Cozen, Charles: Burn case. (Box 4)
    - Crimmins, A. J., Jr.: Hampton, VA. 1/27/65 (Box 4)
    - Criticisms of Project Blue Book. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Crooks, James W., Jr., San Diego. (Box 4)
    - Crowder, C. N., South Hill, VA. 4/21/67 (Box 4)
    - Cruikshank, D. P.: Tucson: Candle balloon photos. 11/26/69 (Box 4)
    - Committee on Science and Astronautics. 7/29/68 (Box 4)
    - Committee for Research on UFOs. (Box 4)
    - Custer, Washington. 1/12/65 (Box 4)
    - Dailey, Norman H.: Tucson, AZ. (Box 4)
    - Damon, Texas case: 9/3/65: McCoy, B. E., and Goode, Bob. (Box 4)
    - Daubert, Louis: Norwich, NY 7/27/64. (Box 4)
    - Daubner, Roland H.: Gills Rock, Wisconsin. 9/13/59 (Box 4)
    - Davidson, Dr. Leon. (Box 4)
    - Davis, Mrs. E. L.: Kilgore, TX. (Box 4)
    - Davis, Isabel L. (Some re. Ward case). (Box 4)
    - Deception Island. 7/65 (Box 4)
    - DeMaine, R. E. L.: Bryn Athyn, PA: Mar. or Apr. 1945. (Box 4)
    - Demler, John H.: Jonestown, PA. 4/5/67 (Box 4)
    - Detroit F-94. 3/53 (Box 4)
    - Disappearances, Aircraft. (Box 4)
    - Distribution Lists. (Box 4)
    - Dittmar, Mrs. George W.: Marysville, Ohio. 1/5 (Box 4)
    - Drake, Frank. (Box 4)
    - Druffel, Ann: Correspondence, Temple City, CA photoLACKING. 1996 (Box 4)
    - Druffel, Ann: Yorba Linda report, photos. (Box 4)
    - Dunbar, W. VA: Tad Jones. 1/67 (Box 4)
    - Dupont Research Society Speech. (Box 4)
    - Earley, George W.: Bloomfield, Connecticut. (Box 4)
    - Early sightings: Investigated by JEM. 1966-1969 (Box 4)
    - Earthquake lights. (Box 4)
    - Earthquake phenomena. (Box 4)
    - Easter, Charles F.: Tucson: Photos. 10/9/67 (Box 4)
    - Edison Foundation talk. 5/69 (Box 4)
    - Edwards AFB: 5/3/57 (Box 4)
    - Edwards AFB. 7/30/67 (Box 4)
    - Electromagnetic cases. (Box 4)
    - Electromagnetic effects. (Box 4)
    - Electronic warfare. (Box 4)
    - Elmwood Park, IL. 11/4/57 (Box 4)
    - Embajada de Chile. 12/3/68 (Box 4)
    - England: Flying Saucer Review (FSR, an UFO journal). (Box 4)
    - England: non-FSR. (Box 4)
    - Epperson, Idabel: LANS-NICAP Correspondence. 1966-1970 (Box 4)
    - Epperson, Idabel: Correspondence re missing briefcase. (Box 4)
    - Evans McIntosh case. 2/17/58 (Box 4)
    - Executive Club: Phoenix. 3/68 (Box 4)
    - Exeter, NH. 9/3/65 (Box 4)
    - Federal Aviation Administration (FAA): Personnel Inquiries. (Box 5)
    - Fahrney, Admiral Delmar S. (Box 5)
    - Farmington, NM. 3/17/50 (Box 5)
    - Fatima. (Box 5)
    - Felty, Johnny. (Box 5)
    - File Index by JEM. (Box 5)
    - Fitzgerald case: Sheffield Lake, Ohio. 9/2/58 (Box 5)
    - Flares. (Box 5)
    - Flickinger: Minot, North Dakota. 8/2/67 (Box 5)
    - Florio, Andy: (Near Benson, AZ) Photo. 3/30/55 (Box 5)
    - Foo-fighter mystery. (Box 5)
    - Ford, Gerald A. (Box 5)
    - Congressman Ford, Henry II: sighting. 4/16/68 (Box 5)
    - Ford, Ruth E.: Lubbock, TX. 2/6/67 (Box 5)
    - Foreign Miscellany. (Box 5)
    - Fort Belvoir case: Australian "ring / cloud" photos. (Box 5)
    - Fort Belvoir Photos: Ring / cloud photo case. Sept. 1957 (Box 5)
    - Forteana. (Box 5)
    - Fort Monmouth. 9/10-11/51, 2/23/65 (Box 5)
    - Fournet, Dewey: JEM re. NICAP. 1970 (Box 5)
    - Fowler, Ray: Correspondence re. "coverup." (Box 5)
    - Fowler, Raymond E. (Massachusetts NICAP). (Box 5)
    - Fredrickson, Stan S.: Burley, Idaho. 10/16/67 (Box 5)
    - Freedom of Information Law: Witness names. (Box 5)
    - French UFO Groups, etc. (Box 5)
    - Friday Harbor. 6/13-14/7 (Box 5)
    - Friedman, Stanton (Westinghouse, NICAP). (Box 5)
    - Fringe Material. (Box 5)
    - Flying Saucer Review: Beyond Condon articles. (Box 5)
    - Fuller, John. (Box 5)
    - Garland, General William M. (Box 5)
    - Ghost Rockets. 1946 (Box 5)
    - Gilham, Rene: Merom, Indiana. 11/6/57 (Box 5)
    - Gill, Rev. William B: Papua, New Guinea sighting. 6/26/57 (Box 5)
    - Goddard, John M.: Grand Canyon, AZ. 4/16/54 (Box 5)
    - Goff, Theodore L.: Angels' Hair: Chadron, Nebraska. 11/8/6 (Box 5)
    - Goldsberry, Jack. 1959 (Box 5)
    - Goldwater, Senator Barry. (Box 5)
    - Goodland, Kansas. 3/8-9/67 (Box 5)
    - Goose AFB Cases. (Box 5)
    - Goshen, Indiana: Manning-Adickes case. 4/27/50 (Box 5)
    - Granada TV: New York. 1967 (Box 5)
    - Gravity Research. (Box 5)
    - Green Fireballs and Meteor "UFOs." (Box 5)
    - Greenwell, Richard. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Flying Saucer Investigation Comm, Akron OH: A. E. Candusso, Larry Moyers. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Goodyear UFO Society. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Institute of Policy Studies: Richard J. Barnet. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Ohio: Cleveland Ufology Project (CUPO). (Box 5)
    - Groups: Miscellaneous U. S. UFO groups. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Queensland, Australia: QFSRB: Brisbane. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Space Optics: Bloomer, John H. (Box 5)
    - Groups: Victorian FSRS: VUFORS (Australian). (Box 5)
    - Groups: UFORI: Stan Friedman. (Box 5)
    - Guam: UFO-Radar case. 1966 (Box 5)
    - Gulfport, Mississippi: S. T. Mellen. 12/3/54 (Box 5)
    - Guseman Gase: St. George, Delaware. 2/9/67 (Box 5)
    - Guy, D. A.: Springfield, IL. 2/3/45 (Box 5)
    - Gwodz, Capt. Joseph: SS Nantucket. 10/7/58 (Box 5)
    - Hall, Richard H. (Box 5)
    - Hall, Richard H.: Correspondence. 1968-1971 (Box 6)
    - Hall, Richard H.: Fund. (Box 6)
    - Hang, Edward J.: Yosemite, CA. 8/15/64 (Box 6)
    - Harris, Waldo J.: Salt Lake City. 11/2/61 (Box 6)
    - Harrisburg, PA: George B. Cook. 6/66 (Box 6)
    - Hartmann, William K. 1969 (Box 6)
    - Havasu AZ: Slater, H. L.. 3/17/69 (Box 6)
    - Hawk, Carl: Sandia case. 4/23/52 (Box 6)
    - Hawks, Ray: Boulder, Colorado. 9/11/62 (Box 6)
    - Henderson, Gary: Earth/Space Science Laboratory. (Box 6)
    - Heflin, Rex: Photos. 1965-1968 (Box 6)
    - Hennessey, Julian: English Researcher: Correspondence. (Box 6)
    - Hewes, Hayden: Interplanetary Intelligence Report. (Box 6)
    - Hill, Betty and Barney: Psychiatrist's statement. (Box 6)
    - Hill, Paul R.: Hampton, VA. 7/16/52 (Box 6)
    - Hill, Colonel Robert G.: Anaheim, CA. 11/6/61 (Box 6)
    - Hillsboro, Kansas: Hoaxer fabrication. 3/22/67 (Box 6)
    - Hillsdale, Michigan. 3/21/66 (Box 6)
    - Hoaxes and Fabrications Holloman AFB, NM. 4/5/48 (Box 6)
    - Holloman AFB, NM. 4/27/50 (Box 6)
    - Hollywood Sighting. 2/5-6/60 (Box 6)
    - Hoover, Frederick J.: correspondence. 1970 (Box 6)
    - Hull, Capt. William J.: Mobile, Alabama. 11/14/56 (Box 6)
    - Hunt, Captain W. R. 5/22/51 (Box 6)